João Pedro Figueira Galhardo Calhau

Curriculum Vitae

Summary

Currently finishing Master's Degree in Computer Science Engineering at University of Évora and at the same time working as an intern at Capgemini Évora. Dissertation theme is related to computer security and it's title is "Digital Forensics Research Using Constraint Programming". During Bachelor's and first year of Master's gained interest in Back-end, Security and Relational Database management Systems. Work solo or in a team, fully capable and willing to learn new things and overall enrich any kind of skill that may be worth it for the future.

Education

2013-2016 Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Engineering, University of Évora, Évora,

Portugal.

Final Average: 13.17 out of 20

2016-Present Master's Degree in Computer Science Engineering, University of Évora, Évora,

Portugal.

Writing thesis. Current Average: 15 out of 20

Experience

Work Experience

2018–Present Intern, Capgemini, Évora.

Working with Microsoft Dynamics CRM 365 and with C# language and also touching on a bit of HTML, Javascript and CSS

Miscellaneous

2014–2017 Vigilante, Cathedral of Évora, Évora.

Interaction with tourists of various nationalities during Summer, usually a whole month

2013 Coffee Attendant, Zoka, Évora.

Interactions with all sorts of people from all sorts of nationalities, also taking orders and preparing them. One month duration

2012 Factory Work, TE Connectivity, Évora.

Worked in the relay creation section inside the factory, watching the machines in case they jammed and fixing them in case they needed to be fixed. One month duration

Bairro da Malagueira, Rua da Melgas, $n^{\circ}5$ – 7000-364, Évora – Portugal (+351) 967157369 • (+351) 266731872 \square joaocalhau6@live.com.pt

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

o Java, C, C++, C#, Lua, Python, Prolog, Groovy, JavaScript

Markup Languages

o HTML, CSS, LATEX, Markdown

Relational Database Management Systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL

NoSQL Databases

Redis

Integrated Development Environments

o IntelliJ, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio

Frameworks

o Grails, React Native, Node.js, Codeigniter, Django

Other Important Technologies

o Bash, Git

Languages

Portuguese Native

English C1

Proudest achievements (In University)

Database with information about Erasmus+ students (PL/pgsql).

Development of a database in PostgreSQL with Triggers and Functions with the help of PL/pgsql

Text based Game like Dungeons and Dragons.

Creation of a small text based game (with text commands) in Prolog language. The game consists of 3 floors (each floor with various rooms, and a final room where one can descend floors by killing a final boss), each level has items, mobs, pets and a simplified light system. The player can equip items, change pets, eat food and fight against mobs or bosses.

Information Theory assignment.

Analyzing a genome, compressing, sending information through a channel, correcting the errors and decompressing. Algorithms involved: Hamming Code and LZW Compression Algorithm

REST Interface to University of Évora's Climate webpage.

Development of a REST interface using Groovy with the Grails framework. The interface consists in collecting data from the University of Évora's Climate webpage (http://www.clima.cge.uevora.pt/) and showing it in a more presentable manner to the clients. The clients could query the interface and it could organize the information in various ways. This interface was later used in another assignment in a Master's class to create an android application.

Additional Information

- Technology enthusiast.
- o Enjoys programming and learning new languages.
- Preferred languages are Java, C, C++ and C#
- Took a modular formation in composites.
- Participated in EIT Health Innovation Day, where we were asked to come up with new ideas to blend technology with the health sector in Portugal. Team won first prize.
- Enjoys playing computer or console games.

Certificates

Bachelor's Degree Diploma.

University of Évora, Évora, Portugal, 2016

Modular Formation in Composites.

Institute of Employment and Training, Évora, Portugal, 2013

EIT Health Innovation Day Winner Diploma.

PACT, Évora, Portugal, 2017

UNIVERSIDADE DE ÉVORA

Academic Services

Certificate

Maria Alexandra Courinha Martins Lopes Fernandes, Director of the Academic Services at the Universidade de Évora (University of Évora) certifies that, according to the records archived in these Services, João Pedro Figueira Galhardo Calhau, holder of the Identity Card nº 14914698 (Cartão de Cidadão Português), with Portuguese nationality, concluded on the first of July, two thousand and sixteen, the Licenciatura em Engenharia Informática (Computer Science Engineering), attaining the level of licenciado, administered by this University, with a total of 180 credits, in accordance with the curricular structure published in Diário da República (2.ª série) nº 55, de 18 de março de 2008, Despacho n.º 8090/2008, having obtained the classification of 13 (thirteen) marks, mention of Adequate and classification of C on the European Scale of Comparable Classification.

This certificate is officially stamped.

Universidade de Évora, 23rd May 2018

R'Academic Services Director

Register: 0602/9119/0252LIC/2016

Payment: 100.00 € Confirmed: Arabela



Certificado de Qualificações

Formação Modular

(Portaria nº 230/2008, de 7 de Março)

Certifica-se que João Pedro Figueira Galhardo Calhau natural de Évora nascido em 11/07/1995, com o N.º de Identificação Civil 14914698 válido até 19/08/2014, concluiu com aproveitamento, em 01/10/2013, no(a) Centro de Formação Profissional de Évora, a(s) seguinte(s) unidade(s) de formação de curta duração do Catálogo Nacional de Qualificações, com início em 13/08/2013.

Componente de Formação	Código	Unidades de Formação de Curta Duração	Carga horária
Tecnológica	5852	Compósitos - introdução	25
	5853	Compósitos - processo de fabrico por cura em autoclave	50

Évora, 04 de Outubro de 2013

O(A) Responsável pelo(a) Centro de Formação Profissional de Évora

M ,

(Assinatura e selo branco ou carimbo)

Certificado n.º 3489/2013













INNOVATION DAY

VENCEDOR

Portugal 2020 - Sistema de Incentivos "Qualificação das PME" Serviços de consultadoria à elaboração de Candidatura ao (Tipologia Vale)

24 DE NOVEMBRO DE 2017





